chromacademy.com 2019-08-02

# hplc training for the analytical chemist l CHROMacademy.com

Hello. Crawford Scientific Ltd./MultiMedia Pharm Sciences, LLC. (together with their affiliated entities, “we", “us”, etc.) know that visitors to and users (“you”, “your”) of CHROMacademy.com (“Website” or “Site”) care about how information about them is used and shared. So we created this privacy policy (“Policy”) to demonstrate our commitment to your privacy. Please note: If you use the Site, it means you consent and accept the terms in this Policy.

Data Controllers

Any personal information provided by you or gathered in connection with the Website is controlled by Crawford Scientific Ltd., Holm Street , Strathaven, Scotland, Lanarkshire ML10 6NB, and MultiMedia Pharm Sciences, LLC., 485f Route 1 South, Iselin New Jersey 08830. Crawford and Advanstar have executed a Data Transfer Agreement in accordance with the standard contractual clauses authorized by the European Commission. You expressly consent to the transfer of your Personal Information (defined below) to Advanstar.

What Personal Information Do We Collect?

“Personal Information” or “PI” is information that can be used to uniquely identify you personally. Examples of personal information include your name, organisation, mailing address, telephone number, email address, and credit card number. In general, you may visit the public areas of the Website without identifying yourself or revealing any Personal Information; however, if you become a paid subscriber, communicate with us by e-mail, post messages to any of our community forums, purchase goods or services, or otherwise complete online forms, surveys or contest entries, any information provided in such communications may be collected as Personal Information. 

We may collect, store, and use the following kinds of Personal Information from you:

Automatic Information: A cookie is a string of data sent by a website to a user’s computer. Cookies help us recognize you when you visit or come back to the Site, and they make your use of the Site more user-friendly and efficient. The permanent or persistent cookies we use remain on your computer after you leave the Site. The “Help” menu on most browsers will tell you how to get notice of a new cookie and how to disable cookies. However, disabling the cookie support function of your browser will prevent our Website from functioning smoothly (e.g., the Site won’t remember you as a prior visitor), and you may not be able to use fully all of the Site's features and information. 

Examples of other information we collect automatically from you and other visitors to the Site include (without limitation) the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; information about your computer; your email address, password, and other log-in information; and information about pages or products and services you have viewed or searched for.

Note: We enable advertising companies to develop banner and other ads for our Website, and the ads may contain cookies. These companies collect cookies sent to your browser through the ads, and we do not have control of, or access to, this data. In addition, we may publish site traffic statistics based on Google Analytics or other sources which are tailored to users based on information derived from cookies. 

Information You Give Us: We receive and store any information (including PI) you give us on the Site or any other way. If you don’t give us all the information we request, you may not be able to enjoy all the features on the Site.

Other Sources of Information: We might receive information about you from other sources and add it to our database and account information about you.

How Do We Use and Share Your Personal Information?

Generally: We use permanent and temporary, session-specific cookies to ensure your visits to the Website are smooth and better customized. Cookies also help us understand which parts of the Site are the most popular, where our visitors are going, and how much time they spend there. When you browse our Website, it collects the IP address of your computer and clickstream data (information that Site users generate as they move from page to page on the Site and click on items). This data is aggregated with usage data from all Site visitors.

We use the information (including PI) you provide to: respond to your requests for goods or services (e.g., to sign up for subscriptions, to register for attendance at our web seminars, live training, conferences, and events, and to access certain online content and functionality of the Site); process and collect payments from you; customize and improve the Site; to send you general (non-marketing) commercial communications, educational newsletters, notice of new Website content - and unless you opt out by following the instructions on this page - other marketing communications relating to our business or carefully-selected third parties whose products and services we think might be of interest to you; and to communicate with you in connection with our services and your concerns regarding the Site and related matters.

We use other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf, e.g., to fulfill subscription requests; maintain our databases; send emails; process credit card information; host our community forums, search engine, website traffic management system, banner ads, web conferences, surveys, and customer request forms; and provide customer service generally. They have access to your PI to perform their functions, but they may use your PI for no other purpose and are required to process any of your PI in accordance with this Policy.

The companies that bring you CHROMacademy, in accordance with the best practices in data transparency and protection, have signed a “Data Controller” agreement setting out how and what we do with your data. [Click to view that agreement](https://www.chromacademy.com/Controller_Data_Sharing_Agreement_Advanstar_Crawford_Feb24_2011.pdf)

Opt-Out Option: You can decide whether you want to receive targeted advertising and promotional information from us, but please note: Unless you opt-out, we create lists compiled from Personal Information (including e-mail addresses) gathered from this Website and may share it with carefully-selected third parties whose products and services might be of interest to you. Every time we collect PI you will be given a chance to opt-out from receiving communications from us and our other uses of your Personal Information. Also, you may always update your communication and other preferences by visiting this link [//chromacademy.com/contact.html](https://chromacademy.com/contact.html) . So, for example, if you do not want us to use your PI to personalize third-party advertisements we display to you, please request this to us in the comments box.

If you accept promotional email from us, any email you receive will include instructions on how to be removed from our promotional email list.

**Other Disclosures** : We also may disclose your Personal Information: to the extent we believe we are or will be required to do so by law; to defend our or another’s legal rights (e.g., to prevent fraud); in connection with the sale or prospective sale of all or part of our business; to enforce the Website’s //chromacademy.com/terms-conditions.html and to respond to a breach or attempted breach of the security of the Site.

We also will provide third parties, e.g., Google and Omniture, with aggregate anonymous data for web analytics and other statistical purposes. This information will be used to evaluate subscribers’ use of the Site and to compile reports on website activity and Internet usage.

Other than as set forth in this Policy, you will receive a notice when any of your PI might go to a third party, and you will have the opportunity to choose not to share such information. Except as provided in this Policy, we will not disclose or share your Personal Information with a third party.

**How Secure Is My Personal Information?**

We are committed to protecting the information we collect from you and have security measures in place to reasonably protect such information. For example, we store Personal Information on computer systems with limited access. When we transmit highly confidential information (such as a credit card number or password) over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol, an industry-standard security measure. Although we transmit the entire credit card number(s) to the applicable credit card company, we reveal only the last four digits of your credit card number(s) to confirm an order.

Please also remember that you play a valuable part in security as well. Your password to access to relevant portions of our Site should never be shared with anyone and should be changed frequently. Remember that any information you voluntarily disclose on-line in any news or message postings, discussion groups, or sponsored content may be collected and used by others without your permission.

Only authorized employees and our third-party contractors are permitted to access your Personal Information, and they may do so for permitted business functions only. Although we use reasonable efforts to secure network communications, the Site, and your Personal Information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us by e-mail or via our Website, and you do so at your own risk.

**Third-Party Websites and Affiliated Links**

The Website contains links to other websites including suppliers, advertisers, and affiliates. We have no control over, and are not responsible for, the content of, or information gathered by, these other websites. We do not endorse any of these websites or the products or services associated with them merely because they are linked to our Website. Furthermore, if you provide any information to parties who operate these websites, you may be disclosing Personal Information, and different rules may apply to the collection, use, or disclosure of Personal Information on these sites. We encourage you to review third-party websites' policies before revealing any Personal Information or other sensitive information. We are not responsible for the privacy practices, terms of use, or the content of third-party websites.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

California's "Shine the Light" law, Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.83, permits users who are residents of California to request and obtain from us, once per year, free of charge, information about their Personal Information, if any, that we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. If applicable, this information includes a listing of the categories of Personal information that was shared and the names and addresses of the third parties with whom we shared the information.

If you are a California resident, and would like to make such a request, please submit your request, in writing, to:

Online Privacy Coordinator  
Multimedia Healthcare Communications,   
LLC 2 Clarke Drive Cranbury, NJ 08512  

or

Crawford Scientific Ltd.  
Holm Street   
Strathaven  
Scotland  
Lanarkshire   
ML10 6NB

**Sale of Business**

If we sell some or all of our assets or our Site is acquired by a third party, your Personal Information will be among the transferred assets.

**Notice of Changes**

Our business changes, and our Privacy Policy and <Terms of Service> will change also. We may email periodic notices about such changes, but you should check the Site frequently to see recent changes. We reserve the right, at any time and without notice, to add to, change, update or modify this Policy simply by posting the change, update, or modification on the Website. Any such change, update or modification will be effective immediately upon posting.

**Contact**

If you have any questions about your privacy at the Website, please email us at [sales@support.chromacademy.com](mailto:sales@support.chromacademy.com) with a complete description and we will try to resolve the issue for you. You may also use snail-mail at the following addresses:

Online Privacy Coordinator  
MultiMedia Pharm Sciences, LLC.  
Legal Department  
131 West 1st Street  
Duluth, MN 55802

or 

Crawford Scientific Ltd.  
Holm Street   
Strathaven  
Scotland  
Lanarkshire   
ML10 6NB

**Your Acceptance of Our Terms of Service**  
By using our Website, products or services, you signify your acceptance of our <Terms of Service> and this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with either this Policy or the <Terms of Service>, please do not use the Website or any products or services.
